# Ryan Maddumahewa

•T: 0426 189 706 •E: rbasehewa@gmail.com •G: github.com/rbasehewa

## **Career Objective**

Having more than two years' commercial experience working with software applications (PHP on Laravel, C# on .NET and Node JS). I am a Master's in Information Technology graduate seeking a software application developer role. I am seeking a challenging position where I can make a valuable contribution to the organisation.

Best Tech skills: REST/ SOAP web services on .NET framework in C# using WCF.

#### **Personal Attributes**

#### **Communication Skills**

- Able to communicate clearly and effectively with various types of people.
- Able to express key information succinctly and professionally.

#### Time management and organisational skills

- Able to work with a group, share ideas, respect other's views and make good decisions to achieve project goals.
- Dedicated, honest and punctual.

#### **Problem-solving skills**

- Strong aptitude to solve problems and make decisions under pressure.
- Always ready to accept new challenges.

# **Key Skills Summary**

Rankings		1	2	3	4	5
Programming languages	Back end	C# on .NET	PHP on Laravel	Python	Java	Ruby on Rails
	Front end	Java\$cript	Node JS	jQuery	HTML/HTML 5	CSS/SCSS
Databases		MySql	MSSQL	Oracle		
Version controls		GIT	SVN	TFS		
Methodologies		Agile on Jira	Scrum on Jira	Business Process Modeling		
Tools		PHP Storm	Visual Studio	Pronto	NetBeans	VS Code

## **Education**

#### **Professional Year Program for ICT**

Sep 2018 - Aug 2019

Performance Education, Adelaide

This program is recognised by the Australian Computer Society (ACS) and assists graduates to improve their employability by developing additional workplace and business skills.

#### Master of Information Technology

July 2016 - July 2018

Charles Sturt University, Sydney

Key learning areas: Java and Python programming, Project management, Object model

## Bachelor of Science in Information Technology

Jan 2011 - Nov 2014

Sri Lanka Institute of Information Technology (SLIIT)

Key learning areas: Relation database management system, Data structures and algorithms, Distributed computer-based software development

#### **Achievements**

Awarded certificate of recognition intern of the month **July 2019** 

Performance Education, Adelaide

Successfully completed Bank of America project

First Technology, Singapore

Published and certified a research paper

Feb 2012

Dec 2017

"A study for software engineering metrics for ERP development projects" in online journal in IJARET.

# <u>University Project</u> (E-commerce development)

Citymart (Research) Dec 2017 - July 2018

Master of IT, CSU, Australia (retail and consumer products)

Objective To introduce "Citymart E-commerce project" for the supermarket, and

> the manager can get the overall decision about the individual stocks analyst looking at the quarters of each year form of a report and design

WordPress web site.

Tools SQL Server Busines intelligence tool R2, Visual Studio, FileZilla, Gantt Chart,

Microsoft Office/ Excel and VBA.

Deliverable I have executed the plan using the Gantt chart and coordinate between

the team members, which development tools to follow.

Items which I

responsible

SRS & Design document, Executable code module and WordPress site.

Result Successfully completed a final year research project "Citymart", which

> requires using data mining technology based on two algorithms for supermarket sales, to predict offers and assist supermarket managers to

make decisions.

## **Professional Experience**

#### Assistant Web Developer (full-time internship)

May 2019 - Aug 2019

Enee Solutions Pty Ltd in Adelaide

- Excelled with Laravel package with PHP, HTML5, SCSS, jQuery and Node is.
- Utilised Autotask tool to integrate API for Enee's client's data which was open tickets and close tickets based in a fortnightly round-up email report.
- Experienced in create and maintain support documentation (Autotask and Jira APIs).
- Experienced with Jira issue tracker and able to fetch the current projects and list of users who are working with current sprints.
- Solid knowledge of SQL with the ability to write queries and optimize existing queries.
- Worked on responsive web projects and web services (REST/SOAP).
- Communicated with the team regularly and work collaboratively to understand the commercial business process.

#### **Assistant System Engineer**

July 2017 - Dec 2017

A Bank of America, Sydney based on First Technology Pty Ltd in Australia (Banking and Financial Services)

- Configuration and management of infrastructure using four steps such as unpacking, cloning, deployment and wiping.
- Worked closely with Cisco products such as routers, switches, access points, video conference (DX70) and IP desk phones.
- Experienced in constructing and warehousing environment.
- Assisted the team with configuring in-house networks.
- Created documentation for user information, site-maps, functionality and usability.

#### **Junior Software Engineer**

Jan 2014 - Feb 2016

Creation Application UK based software development company in Sri Lanka

- Experienced in application development and design.
- Developed an internal company WIKI site and developing initiative moke-ups.
- Ensured all tasks given by senior programmers were finished within a given time frame.
- Integrated Web APIs using .NET and PHP frameworks with Swagger.
- Experienced in Excel and VBA.
- Developed project plan and WBS using Gantt chart.
- Maintained code quality as per the company's standard.
- Having experienced test and deploying high-quality web/ WCF, server-side and database level applications.
- Developed use case diagrams according to business requirement.
- Worked with the agile project management system.

#### <u>References</u>

Kosta Haltis,

Enee Solutions,

Managing Director,

0423 797 947

08 7070 0900

2. Kane Wickman,

Enee Solutions,

Web Developer,

0405 015 385

08 7070 0900